Subroto Burman

♀ 12 Madhav Park Part-3 Near Madhav School, Vastral, 382418 Ahmedabad, India

Summary

Customer-focused software professional with superior communication skills and expertise in various technical platforms. Organized and dependable candidate successful at managing multiple priorities with a positive attitude. Willingness to take on added responsibilities to meet team goals.

Professional Experience

07/2022 – present Hyderabad

Sr. Application Associate

S&P Capital IQ (India) Pvt. Ltd. □

- Deploy/Support Xpressfeed Loader application on client's enterprise level environments
- Assist in solution sizing, deployments, configurations and troubleshooting on-the-go
- Gather depth knowledge of products from a content and delivery standpoint, and assist with pre and post Sales' opportunities
- Bring new ideas for innovation and automation excellence into the technical support process and build tools that will help replicate, troubleshoot, and resolve client issues.
- Assess the technical dynamics within client environments that might impact product performance and recommend changes for improvement
- Involved in product strategy, roadmaps, and user-acceptance testing
- Client-side solution deployments, implementations, upgrades, and migrations

02/2017 - 07/2022

Software Specialist

EclinicalWorks India Pvt. Ltd 🛮

- Respond to customer cases in line with Service Level Agreements.
- Proactively identify and resolve potential problems in an effort to prevent them from occurring and improve the overall customer experience.
- Approach each case with a goal of ensuring products are performing at an optimal level by addressing any underlying or additional problems uncovered during each customer engagement.
- Research and replicate difficult configuration, compatibility or product-defect issues and track results of investigations in appropriate systems also recommend possible solutions and drive resolutions.
- Escalate to appropriate Product Development Team if no resolution can be found, or for bugs or customized solutions
- Develop documentation and the Technical Support Knowledge Base to reduce troubleshooting time and drive faster issue resolution.
- Participate in new product releases and beta cycles to ensure information and training requirements are met to support new product.
- Interact with Sales, Engineering and Product Management and participate in bug scrubs and project meetings to coordinate resolutions to customer-specific product issues and overall technical support trends.

07/2016 - 01/2017

Business Development Executive

Technostack InfoTech Pvt. Ltd ☑

- Developed and tested new product offerings prior to release to assist development team in bug identification.
- Assessed system hardware and software and suggested modifications to reduce lag time and improve overall speed.
- Resolved diverse range of technical issues across multiple systems and applications for customers and end-users across various time zones.
- Responded to support requests from end users and patiently walked individuals through basic troubleshooting tasks.
- Recorded and maintained relevant notes for each client and work order.
- Created support documentation that enabled user community to extend skills, leverage system features and find resolutions to questions without intervention from support team.
- Collaborated with supervisors to escalate and address customer inquiries or technical issues.

05/2015 - 06/2016

Sales Consultant

Credencys Solution Pvt. Ltd ☑

Education

2012 – 2015 Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Engineering

Universal College of Engineering & Technology / Gujarat Technological University CGPA= 8.0/10

2009 – 2012 **Diploma in Computer Engineering**

Government Polytechnic Gandhinagar/ Gujarat Technological University CGPA= 8.57/10

2009 SSC

Gujarat Higher Secondary Board. 75 Percentage

Certificates

 AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals

Skills

Cloud environments

AWS, Azure

Tools:

SQL Server Management studio, JIRA, Microsoft Office, FileZilla

CRM

Salesforce

Database

SQL,MY SQL,Postgress sql

OS

Windows, Linux

Programing Language

Python,